<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Mobile, full-stack and research</title>
        <description>Occasional writings about tinkering with mobile devices and gadgets, all the way to the hardware and conference live-blogs</description>
        <link>http://smart-e.org</link>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 16:51:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <copyright>Copyright 2014 Andrius Aucinas</copyright>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <category>conferences</category>
        <category>tinkering</category>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-blog from SIGCOMM 2014 - day 1]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-19-sigcomm-day1.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-19-sigcomm-day1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Good morning Chicago. On schedule for SIGCOMM today we have a keynote, some SDN, network architecture and middleboxing. As usual, there is also a live-blog at <a href="http://layer9.org">layer9.org</a>.</p>
<p>All the awards first:</p>
<ul>
<li>Best paper awards go to &quot;Balacing Accountability and Privacy in the Network&quot; and &quot;CONGA: Distributed Congestion-Aware Load Balancing for Datacenters&quot;.</li>
<li>Test of time awards go to &quot;Internet Congeston Control for Future High Bandwidth-Delay product environments&quot; by Dina Katabi, MArk Handley, and Charlie Rohrs and &quot;Measuring ISP Topologies for Rocketfuel&quot; by Neil Spring, Ratul Mahajan and David Wetherall.</li>
<li>SIGOMM doctoral dissertation Award goes to Aaron Schulman on &quot;Observing and Improving the Reliability of Internet Last-mile Links&quot;.</li>
<li>the SIGCOMM award goes to George …</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-blog from CoNEXT 2013 - day 2]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-12-11-conext-day2.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-12-11-conext-day2.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Good morning! Today is the second day of CoNEXT 2013 and the sessions today are about trains, wires, tools and falling water. I will be blogging some of the sessions again today, and as before the official conference liveblog is on <a href="http://layer9.org">layer9.org</a>.</p>
<h3 id="session-5-trains-lanes-and-autobalancing">Session 5: Trains, Lanes and Autobalancing</h3>
<p>I skipped the session to patch my own presentation using my colleagues&#39; feedback, but these are the presented papers:</p>
<h4 id="bullet-trains-a-study-of-nic-burst-behavior-at-microsecond-timescales">Bullet Trains: A study of NIC burst behavior at microsecond timescales</h4>
<p>Rishi Kapoor (UC San Diego), Alex C. Snoeren (UC San Diego), Geoffrey M. Voelker (UC San Diego), George Porter (UC San Diego)</p>
<h4 id="fastrak-enabling-express-lanes-in-multi-tenant-data-centers">FasTrak: Enabling Express Lanes in Multi-Tenant Data Centers</h4>
<p>Radhika Niranjan Mysore (UC San Diego), George Porter (UC San Diego), Amin Vahdat (UC San Diego …</p>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-blog from CoNEXT 2013 - day 1]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-12-10-conext-day1.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-12-10-conext-day1.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Kicking off the conference with some explanations about how the TPC selected the papers. The program looks great and I will be covering some of the sessions here over the next three days.</p>
<p>There is an official live blog at layer9: <a href="http://www.layer9.org/">http://www.layer9.org/</a> so I will be covering the sessions and papers that are closer to my field and those that I find particularly interesting.</p>
<p><em>Best full-paper award goes to &quot;Enhancing video accessibility and availability with information-bound references&quot;</em></p>
<p>Our &quot;Staying Online While Mobile: The Hidden Costs&quot; was a nominee for the best short paper award, but alas! The award goes to &quot;Is There a Case for Mobile Phone Content Pre-staging&quot;.</p>
<p>All the papers can be found online at the conference website: <a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/co-next/2013/program.html">http://conferences.sigcomm.org/co-next/2013/program.html</a></p>
<h3 id="-">…</h3>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RaspberryPi as your 3G WiFi router]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-06-30-raspberry-pi-as-your-3g-wifi-router.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-06-30-raspberry-pi-as-your-3g-wifi-router.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Largely as part of another project, but partially for fun I decided to hook up my RaspberryPi to a 3G stick, a WiFi stick and make it share the 3G connectivity to my phones and laptop. Perhaps it isn&#39;t likely you will have all 3 of them but not an actual MiFi or any better connectivity option, but hey!</p>
<p>My setup was therefore:</p>
<ul>
<li>RaspberryPi with Debian (Raspbian) wheezy</li>
<li>Huawei E173 3G stick</li>
<li>TP-Link TL-WN821N WiFi stick</li>
</ul>
<p>WiFi stick was working out of the box as a client, but there was some hassle with 3G...</p>
<h2 id="basic-configuration-of-the-raspberrypi">Basic configuration of the RaspberryPi</h2>
<p>Before starting, I adjusted some of the default RaspberryPi settings:</p>
<ul>
<li>Reduced video RAM split to 16MB</li>
<li>Expanded fielssytem to take up the whole 4GB card</li>
<li>Disabled SSH server :)</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="setting-up-huawei-e173-on-raspberrypi">Setting up Huawei E173 on RaspberryPi</h2>
<h3 id="-">…</h3>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RaspberryPI, 3G and Ofono]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-06-30-raspberrypi-3g-and-ofono.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2013-06-30-raspberrypi-3g-and-ofono.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2013 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>I ended up using ofono with a 3G stick and since that turned out to be more tricky than it should be, decided to write it up here in hope that it might help someone.</p>
<h2 id="using-ofono-with-3g-stick-">Using Ofono with 3G stick:</h2>
<p>Use usb_modeswitch as above, and build ofono from source (1.9.2 as of writing) - there was only 1.6 available for debian wheezy on raspberry Pi. After a bit of fiddling with autotools (because I&#39;m not good at using them), including aclocal, autoheader, libtoolize, automake --add-missing and autoconf, the configuration file is built and you can ./configure &amp;&amp; make &amp;&amp; make install</p>
<p>Some pre-requisites for Ofono:</p>
<pre><code>mobile-broadband-provider-info
libudev-dev
libdbus-1-dev
libglib2.0-dev
</code></pre><p>To also build tools of ofono (in tools/ dir):</p>
<pre><code>libusb-dev
libusb-1.0
</code></pre><p>To use python test …</p>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-blog from SIGCOMM 2014 - day 2]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-20-sigcomm-day2.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-20-sigcomm-day2.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>Starting nice and early with the second day. Just in case you haven&#39;t noticed, papers are available during the conference from the <a href="http://conferences.sigcomm.org/sigcomm/2014/program.php">program webpage</a>. Perhaps unsurprisingly the hall is not very crowded this morning, but the papers look interesting.</p>
<h3 id="session-5-wireless-1-">Session 5: Wireless (1)</h3>
<h4 id="fastforward-fast-and-constructive-full-duplex-relays">FastForward: Fast and Constructive Full Duplex Relays</h4>
<p>Dinesh Bharadia (Stanford University); Sachin Katti (Stanford University)</p>
<p>WiFi has problematic bandwidth indoors due to shielding from walls, etc. MIMO doesn&#39;t help there because of the <em>pinhole effect</em>, where a signal propagates through a cavity in a wall. Instead, proposing full fuplex relay. The key is to do simultaneous RX and TX on the same frequency.</p>
<p>Construct and forward filter does …</p>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live-blog from SIGCOMM 2014 - day 3]]></title>
            <link>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-21-sigcomm-day3.html</link>
            <guid>http://smart-e.org/blogPosts/2014-08-21-sigcomm-day3.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[<h3 id="session-9-scheduling-in-datacenter-networks">Session 9: Scheduling In Datacenter Networks</h3>
<h4 id="decentralized-task-aware-scheduling-for-data-center-networks">Decentralized Task-aware Scheduling for Data Center Networks</h4>
<p>Fahad Dogar (Microsoft Research); Thomas Karagiannis (Microsoft Research); Hitesh Ballani (Microsoft Research); Ant Rowstron (Microsoft Research); Hitesh Ballani (Microsoft Research)</p>
<h4 id="application-aware-network-scheduling-in-data-intensive-clusters">Application-Aware Network Scheduling in Data-Intensive Clusters</h4>
<p>Mosharaf Chowdhury (UC Berkeley); Yuan Zhong (Columbia University); Ion Stoica (UC Berkeley)</p>
<h4 id="multi-resource-packing-for-cluster-schedulers">Multi-Resource Packing for Cluster Schedulers</h4>
<p>Robert Grandl (Univ of Wisconsin, Madison); Ganesh Ananthanarayanan (Microsoft Research); Srikanth Kandula (Microsoft Research); Sriram Rao (Microsoft Research); Aditya Akella (Univ of Wisconsin, Madison)</p>
<h4 id="application-driven-bandwidth-guarantees-in-datacenters">Application-Driven Bandwidth Guarantees in Datacenters</h4>
<p>Jeongkeun Lee (HP …</p>
]]></description>
            <author>
                <name>Andrius Aucinas</name>
                <email>andrius.aucinas@gmail.com</email>
                <link>http:/smart-e.org/</link>
            </author>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>